West Medford African-American Remembrance Project Oral Histories MS123
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
West Medford African-American Remembrance Project Oral Histories
2005 -- 2006
2005 -- 2012
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Shaw, Rosalind
MS123
1.31 Linear Feet 2 oversize boxes, 1 letter size document box, 1 volume
1 Artifact(s)
36 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into fourteen series based on interviewee: Walter Isaacs; Reverend Dr. Oscar G. Philips and Miriam Philips; Madeleine Dugger Andrews; James Sherwood Sr. and Ada Sherwood; Marie Jackson; Alonzo Fields; Edward (Buddy) Clayton; Shirley Kountze; Veronica Lanier; Lt. Col. Edward Dugger; Terri Lyne Carrington; Conrad Sharpton; Clarence Rhone; and Norma Jeffers.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes oral histories created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology Associate Professor Rosalind Shaw. The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project was an oral history project conducted in 2005 and 2006 by the classes of Tufts University and Brandeis University in conjunction with Project LOCAL (Learning Our Communities American Lore). The aim of the West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project was to document the lives and achievements of those who were pioneers in the West Medford community. Interviews with identified leaders in the community and the people who knew the subjects document these achievements. In 2012, an exhibit and a book were created based on these oral histories.
This collection contains project materials.Those materials include, audiocassette interviews, transcripts, student papers, and release forms. The audiocassettes have been digitized and added to Tufts Digital Library. Most of the fourteen series should contain an audio-cassette, a transcript, a digital surrogate of the audio, and a digital surrogate of the text.
Biographical / Historical
Rosalind Shaw is Associate Professor of Anthropology at Tufts University. Her areas of expertise include transitional justice; the anthropology of mass violence and social recovery; child and youth combatants; culture and reconciliation; social memory; the Atlantic slave trade; ritual and religion; West Africa; and Sierra Leone. Shaw earned her B.A. at the University of Leicester and her Ph.D. at the University of London.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Tufts University --Dept. of Sociology; Oral history; West Medford (Mass.) -- History; Rosalind Shaw; African Americans -- Interviews; African Americans -- Massachusetts -- West Medford; African American history; Medford/Somerville history
- Walter Isaacs, 2005; MS123.001; 0.75 Linear Feet; 3 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Walter Isaacs, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by audio and transcripts.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Interview with Alice Isaacs, 2005; MS123.001.001.00001 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview conducted by Kenneth Cleary and Kristina Ceruzzi.
    audio tape
  - Interview with Horace Works, 2005; MS123.001.001.00002 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview conducted by Kenneth J. Cleary.
  - Interview with Cynthia Isaacs, 2005; MS123.001.001.00003 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Horace Works about Walter Isaacs, 2005; MS123.001.002.00001 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
- Reverend Dr. Oscar G. Philips and Miriam Philips, 2005; MS123.002; 0.75 Linear Feet; 4 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Rev. Dr. Oscar G. Philips and Miriam Philips, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Interview with Evelyn Tyner, 2005-03-13; MS123.002.001.00004 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview conducted 3/13/05 at the W. Medford Baptist Church by Gwynne Langley and Toryn Miller Stevens. Present were Evelyn Tyner, Leona Martin, Gwynne Langley and Toryn Miller Stevens.
  - Interview with David Philips, 2005-02-17; MS123.002.001.00005 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview conducted 2/17/05 at Tisch Library, Tufts by Gwynne Langley. Present were Gwynne Langley and David Philips.
  - Interview with Lois Pinton (1), 2005-02-25; MS123.002.001.00006 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview conducted 2/25/05 at the Baptist Church, W. Springfield by Gwynne Langley and Toryn Miller-Stevens. Present were Lois Pinton, Toryn Miller-Stevens and Gwynne Langley.
  - Interview with Lois Pinton (2), 2005; MS123.002.001.00007 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
  - Conversations with Evelyn Tyner and Lois Pinton, 2005-02-05; MS123.002.001.00018 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Conversations recorded at a reception held 2/5/05 by Gwynne Langley. It is also cataloged under series MS123/005, Marie Jackson.
  - Transcript of the Interview with David Philips about Rev & Mrs. Oscar Philips, 2005; MS123.002.002.00002 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Evelyn Tyner about Rev & Mrs. Oscar Philips, 2005; MS123.002.002.00003 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Gwynne Langley
  - Transcript of the Interview with Lois Pinton about Rev & Mrs. Oscar Philips, 2005; MS123.002.002.00004 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
- Madeleine Dugger Andrews, 2005; MS123.003; 0.75 Linear Feet; 3 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Madeleine Dugger Andrews, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Interview with Michael McGlynn, 2005-02-08; MS123.003.001.00008 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on 2/8/05 by Kristina Ceruzzi at the Mayor's office. Present were Mayor Michael McGlynn and Kristina Ceruzzi.
  - Interview with Cortland Dugger, 2005; MS123.003.001.00009 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on by Kristina Ceruzzi at Cortland Dugger's home. Present were Cortland Dugger and Kristina Ceruzzi.
  - Interview with Ione D. Vargos, 2005; MS123.003.001.00010 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview conducted by Kristina Ceruzzi.
  - Interview with Mabray Andrews, 2005; MS123.003.001.00011 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted by Kristina Ceruzzi at 189 Arlington Street. Present were Maybray Andrews and Kristina Ceruzzi.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Ione Vargus about Madeleine Dugger Andrews, 2005; MS123.003.002.00005 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Kristina Ceruzzi
  - Transcript of the Interview with Cortland Dugger about Madeleine Dugger Andrews, 2005; MS123.003.002.00006 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
- James Sherwood Sr. and Ada Sherwood, 2005; MS123.004; 0.75 Linear Feet; 3 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to James Sherwood Sr. and Ada Sherwood, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Interview with Louise Jordan, 2005-03-02; MS123.004.001.00012 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on 3/2/05 by Nakeiha Primus at the home of Louise Jordan.
  - Interview with Judith Carrington, 2005-03-12 -- 2005-03-22; MS123.004.001.00013 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on 3/12/05 by Nakeiha Primus at the home of Louise Jordan. In addition a telephone interview took place on 3/22/05.
  - Interview with J. Sherwood Jr., 2005-03-19; MS123.004.001.00014 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on 3/19/05 by Nakeiha Primus at the South Hall Lounge.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Loise Jordan about Mr. & Mrs. James Sherwood, Sr., 2005; MS123.004.002.00007 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Nakeiha Primus
  - Transcript of the Interview with James Sherwood, Jr. about Mr. & Mrs. James Sherwood, Sr., 2005; MS123.004.002.00008 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Judith Carrington about Mr. & Mrs. James Sherwood, Sr., 2005; MS123.004.002.00009 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
- Marie Jackson, 2005; MS123.005; 0.75 Linear Feet; 4 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Marie Jackson, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Interview with Marie Jackson, 2005-02-27; MS123.005.001.00015 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on 2/27/05 at Marie Jackson's home in Woburn, MA.
  - Interview with Severlin Singleton, 2005-03; MS123.005.001.00016 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted in March 2005 at Cambridge District Court.
  - Interview with Paula Viola, 2005-03-12; MS123.005.001.00017 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Interview was conducted on 3/12/05 at Woburn District Court by Toryn Miller-Stevens.
  - Conversations with Paula Viola and Marie Jackson, 2005-02-05; MS123.005.001.00018 (Reel MS123 Shared 1)
    Conversations recorded at a reception held 2/5/05 by Gwynne Langley. It is also cataloged under series MS123/002, Rev. Oscar G. Philips and Miriam Philips.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Paula Viola about Marie Jackson, 2005; MS123.005.002.00010 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Taryn Miller Stevens
  - Transcript of the Interview with Severlin Singleton about Marie Jackson, 2005; MS123.005.002.00011 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Taryn Miller-Stevens
  - Transcript of the Interview with Marie Jackson, Paula Viola, Evelyn Tyner, Rev. Lois Pinton, 2005; MS123.005.002.00012 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
- Alonzo Fields, 2005; MS123.006; 0.75 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Alonzo Fields, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Mayland Field and Adele Travisano, 2005; MS123.006.002.00013 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Sam Stiegler
  - Transcript of the Interview with Oscar Green about Alonzo Field, 2005; MS123.006.002.00014 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Interview with Oscar Greene (1), 2005-02-13; MS123.006.003.00001 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview conducted on 2/13/05 by Sam Stiegler at Oscar Greene's home in West Medford.
  - Interview with Oscar Greene (2), 2005-02-13; MS123.006.003.00002 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
  - Interview with Mayland Fields and Adele Travisano (1), 2005-03-13; MS123.006.003.00003 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview conducted on 3/13/05.
  - Interview with Mayland Fields and Adele Travisano (2), 2005; MS123.006.003.00004 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
- Edward (Buddy) Clayton, 2005; MS123.007; 0.75 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Edward & Steven Clayton, 2005; MS123.007.002.00015 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Justine and David Clayton, 2005; MS123.007.002.00016 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by
  - Interview with Edward (Buddy) and Steve Clayton., 2005-03-06; MS123.007.003.00005 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 3/6/05 by Courtney Robinson.
  - Interview with Justina and David Clayton., 2005-03-09; MS123.007.003.00006 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 3/9/05.
- Shirley Kountze, 2005; MS123.008; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series is not arranged.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Carol Rickenbacker about Shirley Kountze, 2005; MS123.008.002.00017 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Elmer Kountze about Shirley Kountze, 2005; MS123.008.002.00018 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Shirley Kountze, 2005; MS123.008.002.00019 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
- Veronica Lanier, 2006; MS123.009; 0.75 Linear Feet; 3 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Veronica Lanier, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Veronica Lanier, 2006; MS123.009.002.00020 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Kana Fujisaki
    Oral history; Lanier, Veronica; Dept. of Sociology
  - Transcript of the Interview with Scott Macaulay, 2006; MS123.009.002.00021 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the Interview with Dorothy Elizabeth Tucker, 2006; MS123.009.002.00022 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Interview with Rev. Veronica Lanier. By Kana Fujisaki. At her house in Melrose, 2006; MS123.009.003.00007 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 2/10/2006.
    Oral history; audio tape; Lanier, Veronica; Dept. of Sociology
  - Interview with Scott Macaulay. By Kana Fujisaki. At the Mission house in Melrose, 2006; MS123.009.003.00008 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 3/4/2006.
  - Interview with Dorothy E. Tucker. By Kana Fujisaki. At her house in W. Medford., 2006; MS123.009.003.00009 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 4/11/2006.
- Lt. Col. Edward Dugger, 2006; MS123.010; 0.75 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Lt. Col. Edward Dugger, nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Cortland Dugger, 2006; MS123.010.002.00023 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Ilsa Dohmen
    Oral history; Dugger, Edward Lt. Col.; Dept. of Sociology
  - Transcript of the Interview with Ione Vargus, 2006; MS123.010.002.00024 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Interview with Cortland Dugger on his father in his home. Conducted by Ilsa Dohmen, 2006; MS123.010.003.00010 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 3/3/2006.
    Oral history; audio tape; Dugger, Edward Lt. Col.; Dept. of Sociology
  - Phone interview with Dr. Ione Vargus: regarding Lt. Col. Edward Dugger / by Ilsa Dohmen., 2006; MS123.010.003.00011 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 2/12/2006.
- Terri Lyne Carrington, 2006; MS123.011; 0.75 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Terri Lyne Carrington nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Terri Lyne Carrington, 2006; MS123.011.002.00025 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Eric Misbach
    Oral history; Carrington, Terri Lyne; Dept. of Sociology
  - Transcript of the Interview with Mr. Solomon "Sonny" Matt Carrington and Mrs. Judith Carrington., 2006; MS123.011.002.00026 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Interview with Terri Lyne Carrington / Interviewer Eric Misbach., 2006; MS123.011.003.00012 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 2/25/2006.
    Oral history; audio tape; Carrington, Terri Lyne; Dept. of Sociology
  - Interview with Judith and Sonny Carrington / Interviewer Eric Misbach., 2006; MS123.011.003.00013 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 2/18/2006.
- Conrad Sharpton, 2006; MS123.012; 0.75 Linear Feet; 4 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Conrad Sharpton nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the Interview with Carol Sharpton, 2006; MS123.012.002.00027 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Interview conducted by Vera Belitsky and Maya Lima
    Oral history; Sharpton, Conrad; Dept. of Sociology
  - Transcript of the Interview with Steven Friedberg, 2006; MS123.012.002.00028 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Transcript of the visit to class: Dolores Harris, Carol Sharpton, Whit Jeffers, Rosalind Shaw, Vera Belitsky., 2006; MS123.012.002.00029 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Interview with Carol Sharpton #1: Subject Conrad Sharpton's life / Vera Belitsky and Maya Lima, 2006; MS123.012.003.00014 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 3/2/2006.
    Oral history; audio tape; Sharpton, Conrad; Dept. of Sociology
  - Interview with Carol Sharpton #2: Subject Conrad Sharpton's life / Vera Belitsky and Maya Lima, 2006; MS123.012.003.00015 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
  - Steven Friedberg: Conrad Sharpton Oral History / Speakers, Steven Friedberg and Vera Belitsky., 2006; MS123.012.003.00016 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Interview was conducted on 3/15/2006.
  - Vera Belitsky's recording from class. Committee members, 2006; MS123.012.003.00017 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Taped on 3/16/2006.
- Clarence Rhone, 2006; MS123.013; 0.75 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Clarence Rhone nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the interview with Joan Lovett, 2006; MS123.013.002.00030 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Oral history; Rhone, Clarence; Dept. of Sociology
  - Transcript of the interview with Alice Isaacs, 2006; MS123.013.002.00031 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Joan Lovett interview / By Maya Lima, 2006; MS123.013.003.00018 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Taped on 3/12/2006.
    Oral history; audio tape; Rhone, Clarence; Dept. of Sociology
  - Alice Isaacs interview / By Maya Lima, 2006; MS123.013.003.00019 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Taped on 2/10/2006.
- Norma Jeffers, 2006 -- 2012; 2006; MS123.014; 0.75 Linear Feet; 1 Artifact(s); 2 Digital Object(s)
  These oral histories were created as part of The West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project, conducted by Tufts Department of Sociology and Anthropology, Associate Professor, Rosalind Shaw. The interviews in this series relate to Norma Jeffers nominated for the Remembrance Project.
  - Transcript of the interview with Whitfield Jeffers, 2006; MS123.014.002.00032 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
    Oral history; Jeffers, Norma; Dept. of Sociology
  - Transcript of the interview with Marilyn Smith, 2006; MS123.014.002.00033 (Box MS123 Shared 2)
  - Interview with Whitfield Jeffers: regrading Norma Jeffers / Jen Gerber., 2006; MS123.014.003.00020 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Taped on 2/14/2006.
    Oral history; audio tape; Jeffers, Norma; Dept. of Sociology
  - Marilyn Smith interview: regarding Norma Jeffers / by Jennifer Gerber, 2006; MS123.014.003.00021 (Reel MS123 Shared 3)
    Taped on 2/27/2006. Recorded at too fast a speed. Lower speed and tone on recorder to understand what is said.
  - Place, Race, and Memory, 2012; MS123.015.002.00033 (Box MS123 Shared 2, Box Shared 10)
    Oral history; monographs; monographs; Dept. of Sociology
- Publication, 2012; MS123.015; 1 Volumes
  This series contains a publication that compiles the oral histories and stories collected in 2005 and 2006.
  This series is arranged by date.